您好，美丽的人们知道终端是一个非常强大的工具，它被设计成允许您
Hello you beautiful people know the terminal is a very powerful tool that is designed to allow you to
向您的计算机发出所谓的命令。
issue what is known as commands to your computer.
现在的想法是，计算机将服从这些命令。
Now the idea is that the computer will obey these commands.
我们希望并使事情因此而发生。
We hope and make stuff happen as a result.
现在，在这段视频中，您将学习如何发出您的第一条命令，这非常令人兴奋，但是
Now in this video you're going to learn how to issue your first commands which is very exciting but
顺便说一句，本课程的结构是这样的：课程的每个部分都有自己的小抄，
as an aside this course is structured so that each section of the course has its own cheat sheet that
你可以在这一节的末尾抓取。
you can grab at the end of the section.
所以不用担心记住所有的命令，也不用急着去做笔记来尝试这些命令
So don't worry about memorizing all the commands or rushing down to take notes to try out the commands
我在你自己的电脑上的你自己的虚拟机里展示给你看。
that I show you in your own virtual machine on your own computer.
睡觉向你保证，每一件事都会在最后你能拿到的小抄里为你草草记下。
And rest assured everything is all jotted down for you in the cheat sheets that you can get at the end
每一节的内容。
of each section.
太棒了，对吧。
That's awesome right.
在这段视频结束时，您将已经运行了一系列Linux命令，并且您将开始看到一种模式
So by the end of this video you will have run a bunch of Linux commands and you'll start to see a pattern
Linux命令是如何工作的。
emerging in how Linux commands work.
这将是一堂非常重要的课，它将给你们提供一个基金会将会对你们有所帮助
So this is going to be a very important lecture it's going to give you that foundation is going to help
你知道每件事都是怎么回事。
you understand what everything is all about.
所以，让我们继续往前跳，一头扎进去。
So let's go ahead and jump into it.
好的。
OK.
所以我们要做的第一件事就是开放我们的航站楼。
So the first thing we're going to want to do is to open up our terminal.
有一个快速挑战，让我们看看你是否还记得怎么做。
There was a quick challenge let's see if you can remember how to do that.
请往前走，看看能不能在大约五秒钟内打开航站楼。
Go ahead and see if within about five seconds or so you can open up the terminal.
你可以使用图形化的方法，或者如果你觉得自己特别专业，也可以使用键盘
You can do it using either graphical methods or if you're feeling particularly pro already use the keyboard
您在上一个视频中学到的快捷方式。
shortcut you learnt in the last video.
所以你有五秒钟的时间。
So you've got five seconds.
试一试吧。
Give it a go.
你明白吗。
Do you get it.
嗯，如果做得这么好，你已经在学习了。
Well if so well done you're learning already.
现在我要使用键盘快捷键打开终端，快捷键是Ctrl、Alt和T，还有
Now I'm going to open up the terminal using the keyboard shortcut which is control alt and T and there's
实际上是脑海中弹出的画面。
actually a mental pop up.
现在，从现在开始，我大部分时间都要这样做。
Now I'm going to do it like that for most of the time from now on.
因此，如果您看到终端窗口在我们浏览时到处弹出，请不要感到困惑
So don't be confused if you see terminal windows popping up all over the place as we go through the
当然，我只是使用键盘快捷键，但为了使录音中的文本更容易阅读，我
course I'm just using the keyboard shortcut but to make the text easier to read on the recording I'm
查看并单击放大将使字体变得更大。
going to view and click zoom in will make the font just that much larger.
好的。
OK.
所以当我打字的时候，我应该让它更容易阅读。
So I should make it a bit easier to read when I type stuff.
但是在终端窗口打开时，让我们运行一个名为Echo的有趣命令。
But at our terminal windows open Let's run a fun command called Echo.
现在，echo命令只打印出您给它作为输入的内容。
Now the echo command just prints out what you give it as an input.
所以和我一起键入下面的命令，我们将键入ECHO。
So type with me the following command we're going to type echo.
好的，然后按空格键，我们将输入单词Hello。
OK then press space and we're going to type the word Hello.
现在，当我按Enter键时，我就会说是计算机。
Now when I press Enter I'm going to say it's the computer.
好的。
OK.
实际运行此命令。
Actually run this command.
当我按Enter键时，我们看到计算机的Hello命令。
And when I press Enter we see Hello command to the computer.
所以这是相当酷的。
So it's pretty cool.
我们再试一次吧。
Let's try that again.
好的。
OK.
我们将说ECHO，然后键入ECHO。
We're going to say echo then type echo.
带着大量的臭氧。
With a load of oze.
好的，然后我按Enter键，返回的是Echo。
Ok then I get to press enter and what comes back is Echo.
哦，那真是太棒了。
Oh how awesome is that.
它就像一个山洞。
It's just like a cave.
现在让我们尝试使用另一个名为Cal的命令。
So let's try now with another command called Cal.
那就是ECHO。
So that's echo.
让我们尝试另一个名为Cal的命令，CaO将在屏幕上显示一个日历。
Let's try another command called Cal and Cao is going to show up a calendar on the screen.
因此，如果我们像这样键入cow，然后按Enter键，您可以看到我们得到了当前的日历
So if we type cow just like that and press ENTER you can see that we get a calendar for the current
当月的月份，带有今天日期的也突出显示。
months for the current month with the with today's date also highlighted.
现在我在2017年10月做这件事，当你在看这个并亲自做这件事的时候，这可能是一个非常
And now I'm doing this in October 2017 when you're watching this and doing it yourself it may be a very
不同的月份，但您会得到您键入的点数COW的默认行为是您会获得当前的
different month but you get the point you type cow the default behavior is that you get the current
突出显示当前日期的月份，但这只是该命令的默认行为。
month with the current day highlighted but that's just the default behavior of the command.
好的，现在让Linux命令变得有趣的是，您不必坚持默认行为。
OK now that makes Linux commands interesting is how you don't have to stick with the default behavior.
实际上，您可以将命令的行为完全自定义为您希望它们执行的操作。
You can actually customize the behavior of commands to exactly what you want them to do.
因此，例如，如果我不仅想要当前月份的日历，还想要本年度的日历，那该怎么办呢？
So for example what if I wanted the calendar not just for the current month but for the current year.
但是我可以做的是，首先我可以输入COW，然后是2017，然后我可以按Enter，它将
But what I could do first of all I could type cow then 2017 and I can press enter and it's going to
给我2017年的完整日历。
give me the entire calendar for 2017.
它还会突出显示当前日期。
And also it's going to highlight the current date.
那真是太酷了。
That's pretty cool.
在输入很少的情况下，我们得到了更多的结果。
And with very little typing We got a lot more result of that.
正确的。
Right.
但是你也可以给它一些东西，给每个人一种叫做选项的东西。
But you can also give it something give each come on something called an option.
现在，一种选择是允许您自定义命令的行为。
Now one option is something that allows you to customize the behavior of the command.
好的，我可以输入cow，而不是输入2017，或者我可以只输入dash y。
OK so I could type cow and instead of typing 2017 or I could just type dash y.
这将为COW命令提供y选项。
Now this would give the cow command the y option.
现在，如果我按Enter键，我们还会得到2017年的日历，所以你们可以在这里看到，蒙面的阿什温给了我们
Now if I press Enter we also get the calendar for 2017 so you can see here cowled Ashwin gave us the
2017年的日历。
calendar for 2017.
再次突出显示当前日期。
Again highlighted with current dates.
您刚才看到了两种方法，可以自定义图标行为并为其提供输入，然后您可以
So you've just seen two ways that you can customize icons behavior and give it input and you can give
IT选项，我们将更详细地介绍这两者之间的区别
it options and we're going to be going into a lot more detail about the difference between the two and
他们是如何工作的。
how they work.
但是您现在可能很好奇还有什么其他方法可以自定义命令，但我要说的是
But you may be curious at the moment as to what other ways you can customize commands but I'm going
为了把这种善意留到稍后的时刻，我只想给你们一点小小的
to save that goodness until later at the minute I just want to give you a little bit of a bit of an
概述了可以在Linux上使用的一些不同命令，以便您可以轻松地键入
overview of some different commands that you can use on Linux so you can get comfortable with the typing
然后按Enter键，结果就会重新出现在屏幕上。
and pressing Enter and seeing result come back up on the screen.
好的。
OK.
那么让我们继续看另一个例子。
So let's move on and take a look at another one for example.
您可以使用DATE命令查看今天的日期。
You can see today's date using the date command.
因此，如果我们键入Date并按Enter键，我们会看到今天的日期、时间、时区和年份Pop-Pop。
So if we type date and press ENTER we see that we get today's date and time and time zone and year Pop-Pop.
好的，这很酷。
OK so that's pretty cool.
这是一个非常有用的命令。
It's quite useful command.
但目前您可以看到，我们收到了相当多的文本，而不是终端。
But at the moment you can see that we've got quite a lot of text not terminal.
事情开始变得有点混乱了。
Things are starting to get a bit messy.
我们也可以把它清理一下。
We can clean that up a bit as well.
因此，要做到这一点，我们可以使用CLEAR命令，如果我们键入CLEAR并按ENTER键。
So to do that we can use the clear command if we type clear and press enter.
就像我们刚刚清理了工作区，然后我们现在已经从屏幕上删除了所有文本
It's like we just cleaned up workspace and then we are we've removed all the text from the screen now
因为CLEAR命令使用非常频繁，所以有一个键，因此有一个键盘快捷键。
because the clear command is used so often there's a key there's a keyboard shortcut for it.
好的。
OK.
因此，如果我只需键入echo，然后放入blah，您就可以看到我们有一些文本从
So if I just type echo and then put blah blah blah and you can see we've got some text come out of the
电脑屏幕上有废话，但我们也可以用键盘快捷键来清除屏幕
screen that the computer had blah blah blah but we can also use a keyboard shortcut to clear the screen
键盘快捷键是您最好的控制。
and the keyboard shortcut is your best control.
字母L。
And the letter L.
现在我们都会清空屏幕，这就是我要做的，因为要做的事情很多
Now we all would clear the screen and that's the way that I'm going to be doing it because it's a lot
比每次输入CLEAR命令要快得多，也容易得多。
faster and a lot easier than typing at the clear command every time.
但是你觉得你很自由，你只是明白，如果航站楼突然有了它所有的
But you feel free you do you just understand that if the terminal is all of a sudden having all its
文字消失了，这就是我所做的，我刚刚清除了屏幕。
text vanished that's what I've done I've just cleared the screen.
好的。
OK.
现在我们已经没有很多命令了。
Now we don't have quite a few commands already.
那么，如果您想要输入一个先前发生事件的命令，而不必再次键入它，那该怎么办呢
So what if you wanted to enter a command that evented previously without having to type it out again
也许这是一个特别长的命令，我们不知道你能做什么，你可以按向上箭头键
maybe it was a particularly long command we don't know what you can do is you can hit the up arrow key
在你的键盘上。
on your keyboard.
所以如果我按下拼花地板，我们会看到Echo blah top‘s back up，如果我再按一次，它就会
So if I press the paroquet we see Echo blah blah blah top's back up if I press up again it's going to
清场吧。
go clear.
再一次，随着日期的再次，我们看到了一头牛，以此类推。
And again with the date again we see a cow and so on.
我想您可以继续向上按，然后向后循环浏览您已经运行过的命令
I guess you can keep pressing up and cycling backwards through the commands that you've already run
这是非常非常有用的。
which is very very useful.
您还可以使用所谓的HISTORY命令查看整个命令历史记录。
You can also look at your whole command history using what's called the history command.
因此，如果您键入History并按Enter键，我们可以看到前面的所有命令以及行号
So if you type history and press ENTER we can see all of our previous commands with the line number
与它们相关联。
associated with them.
例如，我们可以看到ECHO命令的行号，它是数字1，让我们这样说
For example we can see the line number for our echo command which is the number one let's say that said
我们才是第一，而不是你能做什么。
that we are the one who was number one and not what you could do.
而不是像那样一路骑着车回到第一名。
Instead of having to cycle all the way back up to number one like that.
我能做的就是看一个潮汐，感叹号，然后是一个。
What I could do is look a tide the exclamation mark and then one.
好的。
OK.
所以一个上面有感叹号。
So exclamation mark on one.
您可以看到我们已经运行了ECHO Hello。
And you can see that we've run echo Hello.
好的。
OK.
那么让我们再来看一看，再来看看我们的历史。
So let's let's have a look again and have a look at our history again.
我们现在明白了，让我们假设我们想要运行回声之类的。
We see now let's say we want to run echo blah blah blah.
伦敦的航班是8点对的。
The London flight is eight right.
如果我按感叹号，再按8，然后按Enter，我们会看到Echo，等等，等等。
So if I press the exclamation mark and press 8 and then press enter we see we get Echo blah blah blah.
所以您可以看到，这是一个有点快捷的方式，可以省去您在可能的数百个
So you can see that that's a bit of a shortcut to save you going back through potentially hundreds of
您运行过的命令。
commands that you've run.
你知道你可以的，你可以像那样更容易地操作它们。
And you know you can you can run them a bit easier like that.
好的。
OK.
如果您想运行您已完成的最近一次，您只需按感叹号感叹号即可
If you want to run the most recent come on that you've done you can just press exclamation mark exclamation
马克。
mark.
我们再一次看到Echo Bah又跑了。
And again we see Echo blah blah blah has run again.
现在这个历史文件可能会变得相当长。
Now this history file can get quite long.
因此，如果你想清除这方面的历史，这是一个分两步走的过程。
So if you want to clear the history of this it's kind of a two step process.
您可以键入HISTORY，并将其设置为C选项。
You can type history and give it the C option.
好的。
OK.
然后添加分号，然后键入History并将其提供给w选项。
Then add a semi-colon then type history and give it to the w option.
好的，那么它所做的就是清除历史记录，然后实际写入这些更改并进行更改
OK so what that does is it clears the history and then actually writes those changes and makes them
永久的。
permanent.
因此，当我们这样做并清除屏幕并查看历史时，我们可以看到我们所拥有的只是
So when we do that and clear the screen and we look at history we can see that all we've got is just
从字面上看，这段历史对你来说不是什么可参考的东西，它不是特别重要
a history quite literally and it's not something for reference for you it's not particularly important
但是如果你想要回溯到这段视频中，你必须要这么做。
but you've got to in this video if you want to refer back to it.
好的。
OK.
现在，最后让我们说我们想要关闭航站楼。
Now finally let's say we want to close the terminal.
好的。
OK.
要做到这一点，我们当然可以点击右上角的X按钮。
Well to do that we could of course click the X button at the top right over here.
但是你也可以输入exit命令，让你自己看起来更专业，所以如果
But you can also type the exit command and make yourself you know just look that much more pro So if
我们按下Exit键。
we press exit.
我们可以看到航站楼现在已经关闭了。
We can see that the terminal has now closed.
当然，如果我按下Ctrl键和D键，您也可以使用Control D键盘快捷键，我们可以看到
And also you could of course use the Control D keyboard shortcuts if I press control and D we can see
航站楼也关闭了。
the terminals also closed as well.
就像我在上一个视频中展示的那样，它允许您键入命令来操作终端，还可以
Like I showed you in the last video and that allows you to type commands operate the terminal and also
关闭它，而不必将手从键盘上移开。
close it without ever having to take your hands off the keyboard.
现在您有了它，您可以直接进入，现在我已经在终端中运行了一大堆Linux命令
So there you have it you jump right in and I've now ran a whole bunch of Linux commands inside the terminal
做得太好了。
so well done.
你的脚已经湿了，我们正在搬家，就像我跟你说过的那样，你可以拿到一张小抄，上面写着
You've got your feet wet and we're moving as I mentioned to you you can get a cheat sheet which covers
我们在本视频中介绍的所有命令以及我们将要使用的所有其他命令
all of the commands that we've covered in this video and all the other commands that we're going to
请在本课程的这一部分进行介绍。
cover in this section of the course.
在本节的最后一课，但是我们在本部分中介绍的这些命令的用例
At the conclusion lecture of this section but the use case of these commands that we've covered in this
演讲在这一点上可能不完全清楚。
lecture may not be completely clear at this point.
这没什么大不了的。
And that's OK.
我不是想在一个视频里教你们一大堆命令。
I wasn't trying to teach you all like a whole bunch of commands in one video.
我在这段视频中想要了解的是，命令是通过在以下位置键入一些奇怪的文本来执行的
What I wanted to get across in this video is that commands are executed by typing some weird text in
终端，然后按Enter键。
the terminal and pressing the enter key.
您还可以看到，命令可以是，它们可以做很多不同的事情，也可以
You've also seen that commands can be they can do a whole lot of different things and they can also
可以针对不同的行为进行定制，但它们似乎都遵循半相似的结构。
be customized for different behavior but they all seem to follow a semi similar kind of structure.
你输入一些文本，也许你有一些选项，或者一些输入，然后你按Enter键。
You type some text maybe you got some options maybe some input and you press enter.
现在能够理解该结构对于掌握Linux操作具有难以置信的重要性
Now being able to understand that structure is of incredible importance to mastering the Linux operating
系统，并利用终端的能力。
system and leveraging the power of the terminal.
在下一个视频中，我将向您展示Linux中的命令是如何构造的，以及我们将
So the next video I'm going to show you how commands are structured in Linux and what we're going to
接下来的内容将成为我们将要学习的几乎所有内容的重要基础
cover next will serve as a critical foundation for pretty much everything that we're going to learn
展望未来，如果您使用Linux，那么您在使用Linux时学到的几乎所有东西
going forward and pretty much everything that you ever learn when you're using Linux if you use Linux
以前，但从来没有真正感觉到，好像你已经，你知道，你得到了，或者你觉得缺少了一些东西
before but never really felt as though you've you know you got it or you felt that some stuff was missing
在你的理解中，这可能是因为你没有看到我接下来要给你看的东西。
in your understanding it's probably because you weren't shown what I'm about to show you next.
如果您是Linux的新手，这将是开始确保一切
And if you're new to Linux this is going to be the best place to start to make sure that everything
进展顺利，您将开始看到Linux操作系统和命令是如何
goes smoothly and you start to see the pattern of how the Linux operating system and the commands are
精心设计，而不是只记住一大堆清单。
designed rather than just memorizing a massive list.
所以，对于那些非常重要的东西，我会在下一个视频中见到你。
So for that super important stuff I'll see you in the next video.